[
  {
    "type": "instructions",
    "note": "Each question is followed by four options lettered A to D. Find the correct option for each question"
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "1",
    "question": "A common feature of people associated with the same ethnic group in Ghana is",
    "answer": "D",
    "options": {
      "A": "name.",
      "B": "occupation.",
      "C": "clothes",
      "D": "language"
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "2",
    "question": "The main benefit of tourism in Ghana is",
    "answer": "C",
    "options": {
      "A": "political stability.",
      "B": "inter-tribal marriage.",
      "C": "foreign exchange",
      "D": "cultural change."
    }
  },{
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "3",
    "question": "The physical environment of Ghana can be protected through",
    "answer": "A",
    "options": {
      "A": "recycling of waste materials.",
      "B": "re-directing river channels.",
      "C": "practising traditional farming.",
      "D": "burning of industrial waste."
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "4",
    "question": "When two air masses of different temperatures meet, the result is",
    "answer": "C",
    "options": {
      "A": "thunder and lightning.",
      "B": "rain shadow zone.",
      "C": "cyclonic rainfall.",
      "D": "relief rainfall."
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "5",
    "question": "Where did the Akan first settle during their migration?",
    "answer": "C",
    "options": {
      "A": "Dormaa Ahenkro",
      "B": "Bono Manso",
      "C": "Denkyira",
      "D": "Asante Manso"
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "6",
    "question": "The period which makrs the beginning and end of adolescence is  ",
    "answer": "D",
    "options": {
      "A": "12 - 19 years.",
      "B": "10 - 19 years.",
      "C": "10 - 14 years.",
      "D": "15 - 19 years."
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "7",
    "question": "The social environment includes ",
    "answer": "A",
    "options": {
      "A": "festivals, political parties and religious groups.",
      "B": "festivals, churches and tourist sites.",
      "C": "settlements, churches and rivers.",
      "D": "settlements, festivals and political parties."
    }
  },{
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "8",
    "question": "An effect of land degradation is ",
    "answer": "D",
    "options": {
      "A": "bad farming practises.",
      "B": "excessive quarrying.",
      "C": "improper layouts.",
      "D": "loss of soil fertility."
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "9",
    "question": "An advantage of chastity to the adolescent is?",
    "answer": "B",
    "options": {
      "A": "avoiding contracting typhoid fever.",
      "B": "gaining approval from adults",
      "C": "knowing blood group easily.",
      "D": "getting the best school to attend."
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "10",
    "question": "People who visit places of interest to enjoy the facilities are called",
    "answer": "C",
    "options": {
      "A": "experts.",
      "B": "travellers.",
      "C": "tourists.",
      "D": "socialists."
    }

  }
]
